Guide to the Sophocles Papas papers, 1900-1998
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Sophocles Papas papers
1900-1998
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Sophocles Papas, 1893-1986
C0052
23 linear feet (43 boxes)
This collection contains personal papers of Sophocles Papas including music scores, manuscript scores, phonograph records, correspondence, music journals, photographs, and guitar music manuals.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Elisabeth Papas Smith and David Papas 1987-1999. Additional materials donated in 2010 by Elisabeth Papas Smith.
Biographical Information
Sophocles Papas was an internationally known teacher of classical guitar. A Fairfax County resident later in his life, Papas taught the classical guitar in Washington, D.C. for nearly sixty years. He also taught at American University in Washington, D.C. Among his former students who have risen to fame are Charlie Byrd and Carlos Barbosa-Lima.
Papas was a prominent figure in the Washington music scene for much of his life. He performed live on radio regularly on WCAP and was a close friend to music legends, Andres Segovia and Carlos Montoya. Papas organized and conducted Washington's first guitar/mandolin/banjo orchestra, and founded the Washington Guitar Society. A prolific writer and publisher, Papas produced articles for scholarly music journals; wrote a column for the music magazine Crescendo; and founded Columbia Music Company, a publisher of sheet music and instructional methods for the guitar. Most notable among his publications is Method for the Classic Guitar. In 1998 Columbia Music Company also published a biography of Papas, Sophocles Papas: the Guitar, His Life, written by his daughter, Elisabeth Papas Smith.
Scope and Content
This collection contains personal papers of Sophocles Papas including music scores, manuscript scores, phonograph records, correspondence, music journals, photographs, and guitar music manuals.
Arrangement
The collection is organized by subject and divided into two series. Series 1 contains the materials acquired in 1987, and Series 2 contains materials acquired in 1999. Since each series was processed separately, the box numbers for the collection repeat. Series 3 consists of scrapbook pages of guitarists and guitars collected by Elisabeth Papas Smith.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds the.
Index Terms
Persons:
Papas, Sophocles, 1893-1986.
Subjects:
Guitar music.; Guitar orchestra music.; Guitar --Instruction and study.; Music.; Music--Instruction and study.
Contents List
- Series 1: 1987 Accession
  This series contains music scores, instruction guides, phonograph records, and music journals included in the 1987 acquisition. Note: the box numbers in this series repeat in series 2.
  - Narciso Serradell (Box 1, Folder 1)
    La Golondrina (The Swallow) Mexican Folk Song
  - Camille Saint-Saens (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Mon coeur s'ouvre a ta voix (My Heart at Sweet Voice) Cantible from Samson and Delilah, voice and piano
  - Nikolai Rimsky-Korsakov (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Chanson Indoue (A Song of India) from the legend "Sadko", voice and piano
  - Erno Rapee (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Angela Mia (My Angel), voice and piano
  - Johann Sebastian Bach (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Lautenpraludium
  - Osman Perez Freire (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Ay, Ay, Ay
  - Hoagy Carmichael (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Star Dust, voice and piano
  - Franz Schubert (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Allegretto in C Minor, piano
  - Unknown Composer (Box 1, Folder 9)
    I Don't Want Him: Oahu "Rhythm Style" Note Course for Plectrum Guitar (octave notation)
  - Anne Robinson (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Flamenco, piano
  - Ernesto Lecuona (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Siboney, voice and piano
  - Johnny Noble (Box 1, Folder 12)
    A Song of Old Hawaii, voice and piano
  - James L. Dixon (Box 1, Folder 13)
    The District of Columbia Is My Home Town, voice and piano
  - Gene Dixon (Box 1, Folder 14)
    There's a Sweetheart in Nebraska, voice and piano
  - Andres Segovia (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Prelude in Chords
  - James L. Molloy (Box 1, Folder 16)
    The Kerry Dance, voice and piano
  - James L. Molloy (Box 1, Folder 17)
    The Kerry Dance, voice and piano with solo parts for C, B flat, E flat, and bass
  - Jules Massenet (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Elegie, voice and piano
  - Jim and Sylvia Symington (Box 1, Folder 19)
    It Takes Time to Know a Country, voice and piano
  - F. Dudleigh Vernor (Box 1, Folder 20)
    The Sweetheart of Sigma Chi, voice and piano
  - Giuseppe Verdi (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Di Provenza Il Mar (What Has Made Your Heart Grow Cold?) Germont's Aria in the second act of "La Traviata," voice and piano
  - W. C. Handy (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Loveless Love
  - W. C. Handy (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Yellow Dog Blues
  - James P. Johnson (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Aintcha Got Music
  - J. Russell Robinson and Spencer Williams (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Ringtail Blues
  - W. C. Handy (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Saint Louis Blues
  - W. C. Handy (Box 1, Folder 27)
    East Saint Louis
  - Noble Sissle, Sidney Bechet and James Tolliver (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Polka Dot Stomp
  - Oscar Rasbach (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Trees Song
  - W. C. Handy (Box 1, Folder 30)
    The Memphis Blues
  - Lew Rose (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Gypsy, voice and piano
  - Unknown Artist (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Hanuka, Oh Hanuka: The Hebrew "Christmas Season" song, accordion
  - Julio A. Vocos Luque (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Romanza No. 2, guitar
  - Ethelbert Nevin (Box 1, Folder 34)
    The Rosary
  - Manuel M. Ponce (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Scherzino Mexicano
  - Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Minuet from Eine Kleine Nachtmusik
  - Alan Dodd (Box 1, Folder 37)
    rue de Blue (bossa nova)
  - Niccolo Paganini (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Capricho No. 13
  - John R. Hansen (Box 1, Folder 39)
    Navajo
  - George Sesoko (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Cherry Blossom: Theme and Variations for the Classical Guitar
  - Scott-Textor (Box 1, Folder 41)
    US Air Force Blues, choral arrangement
  - Felix Mendelssohn (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Consolation: Song without Words
  - Zequinha Abreu (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Tico-Tico, voice and piano
  - Ludwig van Beethoven (Box 1, Folder 44)
    Celebrated Minuet
  - Evelyn Danzig (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Scarlet Ribbons (for Her Hair), voice and piano
  - Scott Joplin (Box 1, Folder 46)
    The Entertainer, piano solo
  - Niccolo Paganini (Box 1, Folder 47)
    Romance
  - Sacha Makaroff (Box 1, Folder 48)
    Gypsy Tango
  - Robert de Visee (Box 1, Folder 49)
    Suite in D Minor
  - Unknown Artist (Box 1, Folder 50)
    Fantasia di Francesco Milanese
  - Jules Massenet (Box 1, Folder 51)
    Elegie
  - Nathanael Diesel (Box 1, Folder 52)
    Suite in G Major for Guitar and Viola da Gamba
  - Stephen Paulus (Box 1, Folder 53)
    Two Moments for guitar
  - Larry Kaelin (Box 1, Folder 54)
    Brazilian Breakdown
  - Hans Newsidler (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Eddie Arkin (Box 1, Folder 56)
    Classical Guitar Suite
  - Lev Knipper (Box 1, Folder 57)
    Poliushko (Meadowland) Theme and Variations on Celebrated Red Army Song
  - Fritz Kreisler (Box 1, Folder 58)
    Rondino (on a theme by Beethoven), violin and piano
  - Leo Kraft (Box 1, Folder 59)
    A New Song, choral arrangement
  - Johann Sebastian Bach (Box 1, Folder 60)
    Prelude
  - Johann Sebastian Bach, Arioso (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - F. Calleja (Box 1, Folder 62)
    Cancion Triste
  - Edvard Greig (Box 1, Folder 63)
    Solvejg's Song (from the Peer Gynt Suite No. 2)
  - Johann Sebastian Bach (Box 1, Folder 64)
    Gigue in E Major, piano
  - Luis Milan (Box 1, Folder 65)
    Pavane
  - Francisco Tarrega (Box 1, Folder 66)
    Marieta
  - Ludwig van Beethoven (Box 1, Folder 67)
    Moonlight Sonata
  - Francisco Tarrega (Box 1, Folder 68)
    Danza Odalisca
  - Francesco Spinacino (Box 1, Folder 69)
    La Bernandina de Josquin (solo) and La Bernandina (duet), lute solo
  - Leonard Gautier (Box 1, Folder 70)
    8 Courantes in Rennaissance Tuning, lute solo
  - John Johnson (Box 1, Folder 71)
    Carman's Whistle
  - Anonymous (Box 1, Folder 72)
    Kemp's Jig and Playfellow
  - Anonymous (Box 1, Folder 73)
    Kemp's Jig
  - John Dowland (Box 1, Folder 74)
    Earl of Essex His Galliard and the Sick Tune
  - Alfred Cottin (Box 1, Folder 75)
    Les Premiers Pas
  - Ferdinand Sor (Box 1, Folder 76)
    Theme Varie
  - Isaac Albeniz (Box 1, Folder 77)
    Leyenda
  - Alonso Mudarra (Box 1, Folder 78)
    Gallarda
  - Anonymous (Box 1, Folder 79)
    El Noy de la Mare
  - Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart (Box 1, Folder 80)
    Sonata No. 3
  - Nilo Menendez (Box 1, Folder 81)
    Aquellos Ojos Verdes
  - Heinrich Marschner (Box 1, Folder 82)
    12 Bagatellen
  - Various Composers (Box 1, Folder 83)
    700 Years of Music for the Classical Guitar
  - Luigi Legnani (Box 1, Folder 84)
    36 caprices in two books (36 caprices en 2 cahiers): Book I
  - Various Composers (Box 1, Folder 85)
    Nineteenth Century Guitar Music
  - Various Composers (Box 1, Folder 86)
    Classical Guitar Editions
  - Various Composers (Box 1, Folder 87)
    The Golden Age: Classics for Solo Guitar, Book One
  - Various Composers (Box 1, Folder 88)
    Mandolin and guitar Collection: No. 9 (first mandolin)
  - Various Composers (Box 1, Folder 89)
    Mandolin and guitar Collection: No. 9 (second mandolin)
  - William Foden (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Listen to the Mocking Bird
  - Isaac Albeniz (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Tango
  - Isaac Albeniz (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Granada
  - Isaac Albeniz (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Oriental
  - Nikolai Rimsky-Korsakov (Box 2, Folder 5)
    The Rose Enslaves the Nightengale, voice and piano
  - Margery McHale (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Grasshoppers, piano
  - Opal Louise Hayes (Box 2, Folder 7)
    One Hand Waltz
  - Erno Bologh (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Clumping Along
  - William Scher (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Veil Dance, piano
  - Domenico Scarlatti (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Sonata
  - Euday L. Bowman (Box 2, Folder 11)
    12th Street Rag, banjo and piano
  - Vladimir Bobri (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Sirocco Tango
  - Michael William Balfe (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Bohemian Girl
  - Unknown Artist (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Believe Me If All Those Endearing Young Charms
  - Johannes Brahms (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Intermezzo, Op. 117, No. 1
  - Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Two Easy Pieces
  - Johann Sebastian Bach (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Gavotte for Guitar
  - Ferdinando Carulli (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Fantaisie Opus 323
  - Various Composers (Box 2, Folder 19)
    The Rosewood Book: 30 Duets for Guitar and Flute
  - Matteo Carcassi (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Melodious and Progressive Etudes for Guitar
  - Various Composers (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Classic American Folk songs for Voice and Guitar
  - Various Composers (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Tunes You Like: Your Favorite Songs Made Easy to Play, voice and piano
  - Matteo Carcassi (Box 2, Folder 23)
    12 Easy Pieces for the Guitar
  - Rev. Ian Douglas Mitchel (Box 2, Folder 24)
    An American Folk Song Mass
  - Bob Oort (Box 2, Folder 25)
    6 Sevillanas for Spanish Guitar
  - Various Composers (Box 2, Folder 26)
    Latin Americana for the Elementary Pianist
  - Joseph M. Estella (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Guitar Songtime: Solos, Duets, Groups, Singing
  - Various Composers (Box 2, Folder 28)
    A Christmas Recital for Piano
  - Various Composers (Box 2, Folder 29)
    The Guitarist's Hour: Book I
  - Various Composers (Box 2, Folder 30)
    The Guitarist's Hour: Book II
  - George F. Handel (Box 2, Folder 31)
    Handel for Guitar
  - Johannes Brahms (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Brahms for the Guitar
  - Irving Bush (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Duet Session: Duets in the Modern Jazz Idiom
  - Various Composers (Box 2, Folder 34)
    6 Authentic Songs and Dances of Moscow Gypsies, piano
  - Mario Abril (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Popular Classics for Classical Guitar
  - Various Composers (Box 2, Folder 36)
    Greek Songs and Dances including Music History of Greece, accordion
  - Various Composers (Box 2, Folder 37)
    200 Songs for Ukulele
  - Various Composers (Box 2, Folder 38)
    Classic Melodies, Great Composers for Piano for Beginners of All Ages
  - Various Composers (Box 2, Folder 39)
    Guitar Folio No. 1
  - Various Composers (Box 2, Folder 40)
    European Guitar and Lute Music: Book Two - German Masters
  - Various Composers (Box 2, Folder 41)
    World Classics for the Guitar
  - Various Composers (Box 2, Folder 42)
    Renaissance Lute Music for the Guitar: An Anthology of Constant Delight
  - Margaret Wigham (Box 2, Folder 43)
    Musical Moods in All Keys for Piano Solo
  - Johann Sebastian Bach (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Two-Part Inventions for Piano
  - John Thompson (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Book for Boys
  - Louise Garrow (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Boogie and Blues for Piano
  - Various Composers (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Authentic Guitar Sounds of Peter, Paul and Mary
  - Various Composers (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Peter, Paul and Mary
  - Various Composers (Box 3, Folder 6)
    More Peter, Paul and Mary
  - Various Composers (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Peter, Paul and mary on Tour
  - Various Composers (Box 3, Folder 8)
    A Little Treasury of Folksongs and Dances: One
  - Various Composers (Box 3, Folder 9)
    A Little Treasury of Folksongs and Dances: Three
  - Various Composers (Box 3, Folder 10)
    A Little Treasury of Folksongs and Dances: Four
  - Peter Ilich Tschaikovsky (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Symphonic Skeleton Scores No. 2, Symphony 6 in B Minor
  - Cesar Franck (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Symphonic Skeleton Scores No. 3, Symphony in D Minor
  - Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Symphonic Skeleton Scores No. 6, Symphony in G Minor
  - Various Composers (Box 3, Folder 14)
    First Duet Album for Two Violins
  - Various Composers (Box 3, Folder 15)
    First Trio Album for Three Violins
  - Various Composers (Box 3, Folder 16)
    First Quartet Album for Strings (two violins, viola, and cello)
  - Signor Friscoe and H. Quali Clark (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Shake It and Break It
  - Various Composers (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Christmas with the King Family, voice and piano
  - Leonard Bernstein and Stephen Sondheim (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Selections from West Side Story for Guitar
  - Various Composers (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Six Lute Pieces of the Renaissance, guitar
  - Various Composers (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Songs for Guitar
  - Various Composers (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Operatic Album for Guitar
  - Various Composers (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Graded Anthology for Classic Guitar
  - Various Composers (Box 3, Folder 24)
    Greek Club Date Handbook: Songs and Dances Every Musician Should Know, piano
  - Various Composers (Box 3, Folder 25)
    International Songs for Guitar
  - Charles-August de Beriot (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Three Duos Concertants for Two Violins
  - Various Composers (Box 3, Folder 27)
    The Moody Blues in Search of the Lost Chord
  - Various Composers (Box 3, Folder 28)
    Classic Melodies: Great Ballets for Piano for Beginners of All Ages
  - Gilbert and Sullivan (Box 3, Folder 29)
    The Mikado
  - Various Composers (Box 3, Folder 30)
    Hebrew Songs for the Young Pianist
  - Various Composers (Box 3, Folder 31)
    Purcell to Mozart: 51 Piano Solos in Their Original Form
  - Various Composers (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Schirmer's American Folk-Song Series: Set 14 - Songs of the Hill-Folk
  - Various Composers (Box 4, Folder 2)
    The Folk Song Sight Singing Series: Book VIII
  - Jane Pickering (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Four Toyes from Jane Pickering's Lute Book
  - Various Composers (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Tumbalalaika and 16 Other Jewish Songs for Singing in English
  - Various Composers (Box 4, Folder 5)
    25 Carols from the Oxford Book of Carols for Schools (Book 1 Nos. 1-14)
  - W. C. Handy (Box 4, Folder 6)
    W. C. Handy's Famous Blues for the Hawaiian Guitar
  - Various Composers (Box 4, Folder 7)
    International Christmas for Piano
  - Various Composers (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Intermediate Guitar Solos
  - Andres Segovia (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Lessons No. 11 and 12 from Follies of my Youth (Le Peche de Ma Jeunesse) for guitar
  - Franco Margola (Box 4, Folder 10)
    8 Pezzi Facili per Chitarra (8 Easy Pieces for Guitar)
  - Various Composers (Box 4, Folder 11)
    The Treasure Chest of Famous Marches
  - The Kingston Trio (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Make Way, voice and piano
  - The Kingston Trio (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Sunny Side!, voice and piano
  - The Kingston Trio (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Close Up, voice and piano
  - Various Composers (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Folk Song Sing Along, voice
  - Various Composers (Box 4, Folder 16)
    The French Funny Book of Popular Tunes in Easy Piano Arrangements
  - Sylvia Van Clief (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Holidays! Holidays! A collection of 21 Songs to Play and Sing in the Holiday Spirit, voice and piano
  - Various Composers (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Classical Guitar
  - Various Composers (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Choice Folk Songs Encore with Guitar Arrangements
  - Various Composers (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Minstrel Songs with Guitar Accompaniment, voice and guitar
  - Various Composers (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Folk tunes for Solo Descant Recorder
  - Various Composers (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Big-Note Carnival, piano
  - Various Composers (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Classical Guitar Recital Book
  - Various Composers (Box 4, Folder 24)
    First Etude Album for Violin
  - Various Composers (Box 4, Folder 25)
    World's Favorite Solos for Classical Guitar
  - Various Composers (Box 4, Folder 26)
    Songs We Sing, voice and piano
  - John W. Schaum (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Theory and Lessons in Loose Leaf Form for Individual or Class Instruction, Book One
  - Various Composers (Box 5, Folder 2)
    The Beginner's Own Book: Folk Songs Carefully Graded for Ear-Training, Sight-Singing, Harmonization, and Transposition
  - Mel Bay (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Fun with the Mandolin
  - DC Dounis (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Higher Development of Thirds and Fingered Octaves: Twenty-Four Advanced Formulas for the Violin, Opus 30
  - Salvador Ranieri (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Method for the Guitar
  - Mauro Giuliani (Box 5, Folder 6)
    120 Daily Guitar Studies for the Right Hand
  - Ryan (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Ryan's True Guitar Instructor
  - Various Composers (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Home Study Lessons for the Hawaiian Steel Guitar from 1 to 12
  - Various Composers (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Home Study Lessons for the Hawaiian Steel Guitar from 13 to 24
  - Various Composers (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Home Study Lessons for the Hawaiian Steel Guitar from 25 to 36
  - Various Composers (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Home Study Lessons for the Hawaiian Steel Guitar from 37 to 48
  - Various Composers (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Home Study Lessons for the Hawaiian Steel Guitar from 49 to 60
  - Various Composers (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Home Study Lessons for the Hawaiian Steel Guitar from 61 to 72
  - Various Composers (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Home Study Lessons for the Hawaiian Steel Guitar from 85 to 96
  - Merle Montgomery (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Music Theory Papers: Ear and Eye Training for the Beginner
  - Ivor Mirants (Box 5, Folder 16)
    The Simplicity Tutor for Spanish Guitar
  - Jack Moore (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Music for the Guitar
  - Laura P. MacCarteney and Margaret R. Pabst (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Intervals and Chords: How to Use Them
  - Fernando Sor (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Andres Segovia Studies for the Guitar
  - Wayne Erben (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Complete and Painless Guide to the Guitar for Young Beginners
  - Thomas Enoch Greene (Box 5, Folder 21)
    A Method for Practicing Scales for Guitar
  - William J. Smith (Box 5, Folder 22)
    Smith's Folk Song Tenor Guitar Course
  - Bob Oort (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Six Studies for Classical Guitar in the Keys of C Major and A Minor
  - Peter Room (Box 5, Folder 24)
    1, 4, 5, and Minor: Guitar Technique and Song Book for Beginners
  - Theodore Presser (Box 5, Folder 25)
    Scales and Cadences
  - G. C. Santisteban (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Carcassi Method for the Guitar
  - Various Composers (Box 5, Folder 27)
    Intermediate Guitar Solos with Commentary
  - Ruth Edwards and Eric Simon (Box 6, Folder 1)
    First Steps in Music: A New Approach to Music for Beginners of All Ages
  - Bruno Henze (Box 6, Folder 2)
    The Classical Guitar Collection
  - Paul C. Herfurth (Box 6, Folder 3)
    A Tune a Day: The Teacher's Manual for Violin Instruction in Group, Public School Classes, or Individual Lessons
  - John W. Schaum (Box 6, Folder 4)
    John W. Schaum Piano Course: A Pre-A Book
  - Nola Arndt (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Teadch Yourself to Play the Guitar
  - Harry A. Taussig (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Instrumental Techniques of American Folk Guitar
  - Barry Kornfeld (Box 6, Folder 7)
    The Folk Guitarist's Manual: American Folk Guitar Techniques and Songs
  - Donald Garwood (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Masters of Instrumental Blues Guitar
  - Gene Leis (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Instruction Chord Book for Guitar
  - Jerry Silverman (Box 6, Folder 10)
    A Folksinger's Guide to Note Reading and Music Theory: A Manual for the Folk Guitarist
  - Matteo Carcassi (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Carcassi Classical Guitar Method
  - Jack Marshall (Box 6, Folder 12)
    The Art of Finger Style Guitar
  - Herbert Forrest Odell (Box 6, Folder 13)
    Odell Method for the Mandolin
  - Jerry Snyder and Ralph Higgins (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Comprehensive Guitar Method: Student Book
  - Jerry Snyder and Ralph Higgins (Box 6, Folder 15)
    Comprehensive Guitar Method: Teacher's Manual
  - G. L. Lansing (Box 6, Folder 16)
    Excelsior Method for Banjo
  - Lorina Havill (Box 6, Folder 17)
    You Can Sight Read: Book 1 - The Pleasures of Piano Sight Reading Through Keyboard Harmony and Technique
  - Harry Volpe and Victor Frank (Box 7, Folder 1)
    The New Handy Guitary Method
  - Irene Lorence (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Spitfire McKenney New Quick Learning System, ukelele
  - Joseph M. Estella (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Smith's How to Play Finger Picking Style Guitar
  - Edwin H. LeMare (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Adantino
  - William C. Stahl (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Stahl's International Banjo Method
  - Peter Seeger (Box 7, Folder 6)
    The Folksinger's Guitar Guide
  - Bernard Wagness (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Piano Course Book One
  - John Thompson (Box 7, Folder 8)
    John Thompson's Modern Course for the Piano: The First Grade Book
  - Bernice Frost (Box 7, Folder 9)
    At the Piano: Book Two
  - Mel Bay (Box 7, Folder 10)
    The Mel Bay Classic Guitar Method Complete in Five Volumes: Volume 1
  - Mel Bay (Box 7, Folder 11)
    The Mel Bay Classic Guitar Method Complete in Five Volumes: Volume 2
  - Mel Bay (Box 7, Folder 12)
    The Mel Bay Classic Guitar Method Complete in Five Volumes: Volume 3
  - Mel Bay (Box 7, Folder 13)
    The Mel Bay Classic Guitar Method Complete in Five Volumes: Volume 4
  - Mel Bay (Box 7, Folder 14)
    The Mel Bay Classic Guitar Method Complete in Five Volumes: Volume 5
  - Anita Sheer and Harry Berlow (Box 7, Folder 15)
    Flamenco Guitar Method for Beginners
  - Alfred d'Auberge and Morton Manus (Box 7, Folder 16)
    The New Guitar Course
  - Matteo Carcassi (Box 7, Folder 17)
    Carcassi Classical Guitar Method - New Revised Edition
  - Joe Fava (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - John Stainer (Box 7, Folder 19)
    Novello's Music Primers and Educational Series: Harmony Lessons
  - Charles Duncan (Box 7, Folder 20)
    The Art of Classical Guitar Playing
  - Joseph Castle (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Guitar Workshop
  - Thomas B. Pitfield (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Musicianship for Guitarists
  - Ivor Mairants (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Method for 12 String Guitar
  - Mary Elizabeth Clark (Box 8, Folder 4)